what's going on ladies and gentlemen
welcome back to another one and in this
video we're doing another product review
on a pretty cool fishing rod and reel
combo we're doing a review on the lse
mock smash bait casting combo now this
rod and reel comes in at a medium heavy
fastaction rod and these things are
super cool it's a 7t 2in rod and I'm
super excited about it so we're going to
talk about this thing and just tell you
what I think about it we're going to
give it some cast and try and catch a
fish today where out in the kayak so
let's see what we can do we're going to
talk about this thing let's jump into
it so as we start to break this thing
down I'm just throwing today I'm
throwing a weight weighted Texas Rig um
it's kind of like what what I like to
start with I don't like to start with
too light of a weight on a new rod and
just kind of looking at it obviously
it's got the red and black black finish
which I think looks super slick um it is
kind of one of the things that caught my
attention when I was looking for another
rod and reel I think the red and black
finish looks super nice you have a
little grip here you know kind of where
your handrest which I think is also a
nice little plus it's there definitely
very grippy but yeah I think it looks
really really nice I think the red and
black finish looks pretty slick it kind
of caught my eye to start with um but as
we look at the rod I think the rod
really shines here at the medium heavy
fastaction rod that's really what like
to see in my bait casting combos um I
don't really like anything smaller than
that and I don't really like anything
heavier than that I just feel like at
the medium heavy fast action you uh you
really get a lot of feel in your Rod so
you can kind of feel every little bite
that you get um I put a 12 lb
monofilament on here started a little
bit smaller with the line just because I
wasn't sure a lot of the times you know
I'll start with a monofilament or a
fluorocarbon um then once I get more
adjusted to the combo that I'm using you
know then I'll throw a braided line on
there or something like that it seems
like it casts really really well I will
say it seems like the re the Reel seems
maybe a little cheap it seems like it's
kind of plasticky um and another thing
to note too this is my second time ever
using this combo and it already has some
scuffs on it so I don't know if it's the
matte finish to this if the paint just
chips really easily but that was one of
the things that I kind of noticed that I
wasn't super happy about obviously not
that big a deal you know it's still
going to be used for it's still going to
get the job done and do what it's
supposed to but I just kind of would
expect with a more expensive bait caster
that you know it would hold up better
not to say that it's not going to stand
the test of time I think that it will
the rod definitely will there's no
questions about that it definitely feels
like they put time and effort into this
rod and it doesn't seem like it's made
cheaply or anything like that but the
Reel does I'd say that the rod
definitely shines in this situation but
all in all you know you get a 751 gear
ratio which I think is pretty standard I
don't have anything to say too bad about
that I think it's good you're definitely
real fast enough it's got eight bearings
in it which is pretty good you know you
can definitely tell that it's smooth
when you reel it in and all that um I
was just kind of surprised that you know
with the way they made this and the
price point that the Reel doesn't seem
just a little bit better um these grips
here you know they do have a little
grippy
um like part that kind of comes up here
you can see the grip on the Reel here
but it just the The Reel does seem kind
of flimsy kind of cheesy they definitely
could have maybe put a little bit more
time and effort into making some better
grips for them but it's not too bad it
definitely sits in your hand good um I
think they got this in the right spot
here to put your finger in one thing
that I thought was a little odd with the
Reel and this could be standard for lose
I'm not really sure but your hook SL lot
here is actually behind the Reel almost
at the end of the rod I'm not really
sure why they did that you know and it's
not a big deal I just thought it was a
little odd um you put it way back here
and I'm kind of used to normally your
you know it being up here not really the
end of the world it's kind of out of the
way so the hook doesn't hit a bunch of
stuff but I probably would have rather
just saw it be up here in its normal
spot but maybe that's something that
lose does and if there's a reason behind
that put a comment down below because
I'm honestly not sure um I couldn't
really find anything on it so I'm not
sure what that's all about I do like on
the Reel though that the brakes are
numbered so you can see where you're at
right now I have it set to half I'm at
the five on the brakes and you can go
all the way up to 10 or obviously all
the way down to zero I did cast it a few
times at zero and it seemed like it was
uh prone to
backlashing and I'll actually cast this
thing out as far as I can and show you
guys right now I have it at half and if
I really rip it out there it casts
pretty good there's no issue with
backlashing I didn't even have to touch
the Reel but if I put it down to zero it
definitely looks like it's going to bird
nest um I did get a pretty nasty bird's
nest the last time I tried this but I'll
try it just for you guys so we got it
all the way down to
zero and you can see pretty nasty bird's
nest hopefully I can get that out but
I'm going to get this bird's nest out
here I'll just have to pull it out and
give me a minute guys and we'll get back
to it here a few moments later okay so I
was able to get the birds nest out but
I'll be honest that was a pretty gnarly
bird's nest I had to pull dang near half
the Reel out and uh I don't know if
that's just because the Reel seems like
it's you know on the cheaper end of the
spectrum but you're definitely I would
recommend keeping those brakes up to
halfway if not even higher um but at
halfway it seems like you're pretty safe
I mean I don't even really have to put
my thumb on it at halfway and I can cast
as hard as I want but I just feel like
with some of my reels I know I can turn
the brakes all the way down and cast as
hard as I want I don't have to have an
issue with it you know maybe you have to
put your thumb on it a little bit but
with this guy it Birds Nest even before
your lure hits the water which isn't
great but I mean at the price point I
think you know right around 150 bucks
for the whole combo not the end of the
world but I would say you know for the
price you could probably buy you know an
individual rod and an individual reel
and possibly get a better bang for your
buck one rod that I would definitely
recommend checking out one combo is uh
the Abu Garcia Max Pro I actually did a
review on that I'll link that in the top
of the video here but that reel you know
is actually cheaper than this one that
combo is cheaper than this one and this
is actually the first lse that I've ever
owned so I can't really speak for all
the other lse but I'm a big Abu Garcia
fan so you know maybe that's just the
way that L are but with that being said
the rod definitely shines here you do
have a nice grip at the end here that
feels pretty good it's definitely more
than enough to do a two-handed cast
really all in all guys I think the only
downside to this combo is the Reel but
with that being said it does still seem
like it's a pretty decent reel I don't
have too much bad to say about it the
gear ratio is good and the eight
bearings I mean that's something to note
too you know that is obviously pretty
quality I just wonder that if the
bearings that they put in there maybe
weren't topnotch or something but I do
like it you know I'm excited to use this
thing um obviously it looks really nice
I keep kind of saying that um but for
the price I mean you probably can't go
wrong but I think you could definitely
Express other options all in all though
guys if you want to check this reel out
I will link it in the description down
below and uh I hope you guys enjoyed
this video if you guys want to see more
product review videos make sure you
subscribe to the channel and like the
video and we'll see you guys in the next
one peace